The White Diamond is a documentary film directed by Werner Herzog.
This 2004 documentary by Werner Herzog diaries the struggle of a passionate English inventor to
design and test a unique airship during its maiden flight above the jungle canopy.
Narrator (voice), played by Werner Herzog.
Self, played by Graham Dorrington.
Self, played by Annette Scheurich.
Self, played by Marc Anthony Yhap.
Self (archive footage), played by Dieter Plage.
Self (archive footage), played by Adrian de Schryver.
The White Diamond is a 2004 documentary film by Werner Herzog.
It illustrates the history of aviation and depicts the struggles and triumphs of Graham Dorrington, an aeronautical engineer,
who has designed and built a teardrop-shaped airship which he plans to fly over the forest canopies of Guyana.
It features music composed by Ernst Reijseger, which was
re-used in Herzog's 2005 film The Wild Blue Yonder.
Most of the film focuses on Dorrington's flights near Kaieteur Falls, in Guyana.
Dorrington discusses the mechanics of his flight, as well as his own struggles with uncertainty
and the "heaviness" he feels after the death of the cinematographer Dieter Plage.
The film also explores the Kaieteur Falls themselves, a local man named Marc Anthony Yhap, a diamond miner, and the
white-tipped swifts (Aeronautes montivagus) which roost in an inaccessible cave behind the falls.
The film holds a score of 83 (based on 12 reviews) on the film review aggregator website
Metacritic and a score of 90% (based on 20 reviews) on Rotten Tomatoes.
The film explores themes of hot air balloon,
waterfall, aviation, airship, jungle.